Hey, we are back to play some AI video.
We have a lot of new updates coming up
and new AI video models sooner, but one
of my favorite Laura models in LTX 2.3
has updated just last week. The
multi-subject reference is now updated
to version two. Version two has improved
consistency, improved stability of
overall objects, not much flickering or
subjects with composition issues, and
improved scene logic since the video
reasoning is also trained from the
Lycoris Studio. So, they have been
making this Laura model and keep
updating to newer versions, and the
reference to video is one of my favorite
things to play around with. Since AI
video started getting reference to video
generation, we can use just one image to
represent the subjects, characters,
objects, anything in your video content,
and generate multiple scenes that have
almost close consistency. Right now, as
you can see on my screen, this is one of
the demos, a music video demo that I
created just last night. Pretty fun.
This is using the MSR version two Laura
model to create in ComfyUI. Before this
video, I tried it with some older
virtual characters that I created
before. Just playing around with those
motions, seeing if close-up shot, far
shot, or those camera panning and moving
have really improved compared with the
MSR version one. And yes, some of that
has been improving. The colorations are
a little better than the previous
versions, and the character consistency
is doing better, especially this guy
here. Those hairstyles, when you see the
close-up, that jacket with some neon
light color, light strap, even in
multiple angles, you will see that it
stays the same jacket, the same
identification. So, yeah, we will be
playing around with this, checking out
how we can use it. Last time I did this
workflow and updated that as well. Last
time was using a female character doing
a music video style, and this time also,
we will be using some multiple shots.
One thing I like about this Laura model
is that even though I am using the older
workflow and just change this Laura
model to the MSR version 2, as you can
see right here, it works. But one thing
is that throughout my testing, the
frames here using the custom nodes of
LyCORIS Studio, this is called the
LyCORIS MSR, you better turn the frame
counts a little bit higher, like 41. Or
even in the newer versions, they have
50, 65 frame counts. That will be
getting even better. So, I will be
trying out the updated versions as well
of this custom node. Even I have not
updated from the previous versions of
this custom node and tried the frame
counts as low as 17 here, generating a
bunch of 15 seconds, 10 seconds video
clips of this music video. I can even
get pretty good results with these
settings. So, I assume that after
updating that custom node and tweaking
the settings to the highest, it will be
getting even better, sharpening those
colorations and the objects staying more
solid. But still, as you can see right
here, it is still good. And after all
the short video clips combining together
like this music video, it still looks
pretty well. It does have a lot of big
improvement compared with the MSR
version 1 Laura model.
Back then, you can check out my video on
this channel. That was the previous
version that I recorded before, trying
with the MSR version 1. As you can see,
that is the same workflow. Of course,
that video quality is not as good as
what you see in the newer versions. The
character consistency sometimes is lost.
Some details, especially in the close-up
shot of the face, some marks are not
exactly what they should be. But in
version 2, so far I tried with this
character, especially it has tattoos on
the neck, both sides and the hands. It
can be generated even in multiple
scenes. Of course, it is not going to be
exactly the same pattern or the same
drawing art of that tattoo. But you can
still see the similarity is very
consistent in terms of what we are
talking about in AI video generation.
You see, even in different angles, far
shot, close shot, and some of the shots
here, these tattoos still look like what
they are. The shape of that can stay
there.
My reference image is actually not that
good. This is just a quick generation
using the Cray 2 text to image only. But
then you can see here we got the tattoos
on both sides of the neck and it is not
even created the close-up face shot in
this character sheet. So this character
sheet is just a demo, not the best that
can be generated, but still those
details are able to be referenced from
the Laura model.
Multiple shots in here, especially this
part when the character is doing a
turnaround and the camera orbits, those
elements pretty much remain the same
consistent character styles. And then
when it goes to the studio here singing,
you see the colorations of the outfit
and those patterns of tattoos. It looks
like it can replicate the styles of
clothing easily with this pattern. So I
would say the MSR version 2 does a lot
better for consistency. Even in some
shots like this one, the first 1 second
does not show the character in the first
frames. You will not have the character
here, but due to the improvement of this
Laura model, when we get to the second
frames and the character starts to
appear, you see the consistency of the
character styles referencing is getting
there.
This is a lot of the time when we play
around with image to video. You are hard
to get characters that appear in the
first frames and then show up in the
middle of the video duration.
That is like 99% won't happen, but using
reference to video that can be done. In
some kind of video content like this,
you can use another presentation like
entering the door and you see this
character.
At the beginning of the frames you do
not see the character, but then it walks
in. This character comes to the table
and you see the character with just the
same outfit, the face, hairstyles as
well.
Of course, to be picky, the tattoos are
not going to be exactly the same tattoo,
but the AI model tries its best to
replicate those styles.
So yeah, we can try out some examples
and also run with the version one as
well.
I put the version two video output here.
This is the beginning video clip of that
MV and I try to generate again.
This will be the one of the generation
here and the one that I am going to
generate is going to choose the MSR
version one.
And then going to select the version
one. We are going to use the same
settings, everything the same here. Also
the audio, same.
The text prompts here using the prompt
relay also not going to change. Just
exactly like this video's input and see
how this generation looks. So let us
wait for the result and we will compare
afterward.
Okay, so here are the two results. The
one labeled as using the MSR version one
just generated and the one that is the
version two that I previously generated
and stitched with the full video.
And this model here,
version one,
you see the face. The last part here is
a little different compared with what we
have in the reference image character.
And you see the consistency is obviously
improved a lot in version two.
And the version one, that face kind of
looks a little different.
Here, I just got a good timing to pause
both video outputs and we can see
clearly. Version one, obviously the face
does not look like the reference image.
Not talking about the facial
recognition, but when we see those
mustache and hairs on the face, it
almost looks like a teenager in this
video. It does not really follow the
aging of how this character looks. In
other words, version two does a little
bit more like the character, but still
to be honest, version two is still not
able to really get the character's face.
Or maybe it is my fault that the
reference image does not have a close-up
shot, but most likely, even if you have
a close-up shot or not, the facial
recognition is not that 100% replicate
of the face. I will try in other videos
that have a close-up shot of the
reference image later, and you guys can
see if that really affects it or not.
But, from my experience of running this,
the facial recognition is not going to
be 100% replicating that face.
Well, some Patreon members have asked
before, and this is the answer. By just
using the MSR LoRA models, you will not
be able to get that face exactly the
same.
We have to do some little tricks to have
the face swapping or doing the face with
that specific character LoRA in order to
achieve more accuracy. The reference to
image or reference to video is just a
quick way to help you mimic the overall
character styles. From what I am using
so far of AI video, even running some
frontier AI video models, still none of
them are able to replicate exactly the
same face. Instead, it is most likely
the outfit and how the character's body
type are able to follow referencing.
Okay, so I have this image generated
using Creazu. This workflow is just a
text-to-image workflow I demonstrated in
a previous video. Going to here, we
finally use another seed number that has
a close-up shot like this. Of course,
this will help a little for the face
consistency, but if you talk about
really the identity of that face, to be
honest, it will not happen for reference
to video. So, I am going to use this
image, going back to here, and put this
image as an input.
Running exactly the same text prompts
again and see how that looks.
By the way, we are going to use this V2
here, and I am going to label this as V2
second. The V1, of course, very clearly
we have seen the answer, so I do not
think we need to compare the V1 again.
Let us try with the V2 that has a
close-up face shot and the previous one
that did not have a close-up face shot,
and compare that referencing.
And for all this input, same one. Going
back to using the version two MSR LoRA
model and going to run this and see how
that looks.
The error here does not matter because
this was the disconnected video
combined, so just let it have the error.
Okay, so this video is generated with
this reference image. Although we got a
close-up shot of the face like this for
referencing, you will see that the
reference to video, mostly for this kind
of referencing, the character sheet.
Yes, it is able to have the consistent
styles for the character's outfit. Like
this sweater, it is exactly what it is.
And some of the accessories or tattoos
on the skin are going to be similar. But
if you are talking about the facial
recognition, this has been discussed in
our Patreon Discord group as well. We
have found out that it is not going to
work for reference to video. It does not
matter how high sampling steps or how
high precision of your AI models is.
You go to BF16 like the one I am using
here, or even if you have a chance to
get FP32, it might get a higher chance
of the facial recognition likeness, but
it is not going to be exactly the same
face pasted on or replicated in the
video content. So this is going to be a
con for reference to video. The exact
character identity will not be able to
get that face to the video content. That
is why in the last few videos I was
talking about using Creater 2 training
Laura. And for LTX video or other AI
video as well, if you can do it for the
repeating usage of a character, then
consider training that character's Laura
models.
That is the best way to go. That is the
highest consistency for your character's
facial recognition.
The reference to video just helps you to
have the outfit or how the character's
style is going to look alike. About 80%
I would say if you use high precision AI
video models. In that case, going back
to here, we got this video that I was
using for the long video output. And
this one, as you can see, of course,
obviously this is not going to be the
same character's face. And both outputs
here, you see the facial recognition is
really similar. So, here is a good pause
timing where you see both characters,
although using a close-up shot in this
one that I am highlighting, the face is
a little different. But then you still
see the similarity. This is coming from
the LTX model's training, I would say,
for that face without character Laura.
It feels like the pattern of what it is
referencing the images, but then not
exactly that character from the image. I
think some people might know what I mean
if you have tried reference to video a
lot, even in other AI video models, or
even go to some frontier paid models, it
still happens like this. And that is the
con of reference to video. You always
have to fight with the consistency of
your facial identity.
So, I will suggest that if you are
having characters that you are really
using for repetitive video content, then
just train your Laura models for the
character. That is the best way to do.
Otherwise, just like this one, for me it
is a demo video, so I will not
specifically train the Laura models
because of this demo video.
That is common sense. But if you are
really using a character for your video
content repetitively, then of course the
best way is to train a Laura model for
that. The reference to video is good
only for the character's outfit, the
style consistency only. And I will see
you guys on the next one.
>> Sound of a gentle acoustic guitar
picking.
>> [music]
>> Soft vinyl crackle and heavy.
Slow sigh.
I know you're awake.
>> [music]
>> I can hear you breathing.
Just
let me talk for [music] a minute. Turn
the beat up a little bit in the
headphones.
Yeah, just like that.
I sit by your bedside
[music and singing]
watching you breathe, trying to find the
right words, but I'm struggling to speak
cuz I look at your [music] face and I
see my own flaws. I look at your hands
and I remember the wars
[singing and music] that I fought in my
head just to keep us afloat. I was
drowning in stress, [music] barely
keeping the boat from sinking. I'm sorry
for the nights you heard yelling,
[music] for the times I was present,
[singing] but my mind was elsewhere,
dwelling on bills on the table, on the
fridge being bare, on the looks that
they gave [music] us, the cold empty
stares. I was trying to build you a
castle from dirt, but I ended [singing]
up hurting you more with the hurt I was
carrying, kid. [music] I was breaking my
back just to keep the wolves out, to
keep the roof from the crack, but I know
it don't [singing] matter the excuses I
make when I see the reflection of my own
mistakes [music] in your eyes. So, I'm
swallowing pride, writing this down
[music] just to say I'm sorry. I tried
to hide all the pain, but I'm taking the
mask off. I'll carry [music] the heavy,
I'll handle the task off. Your
shoulders, you're just a kid, you should
be playing [music] with toys, not
worrying [singing] about the noise or
the grown-up boys playing games with my
life, but I swear [music] on my soul I'm
going to fix it. I'm going to make us
whole.
>> [singing]
[music]
>> So, go to sleep. Don't you worry about
[music and singing] a thing. I'll fight
the dragons, I'll clip their wings. I
know the world [music and singing] is
heavy, I know it's been cold, but I'm
your shield, kiddo. So, I'm told you.
The road's [music] been bumpy, the tires
are bald, but I'm standing right here. I
won't let you fall. So, [music] close
[singing] your eyes.
Let the melody guide you.
I promise [music] you, kid.
I'm right here beside you.